<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meaning of life | Academic</title>
    <link>%20nastarkov.github.io/category/meaning-of-life/</link>
      <atom:link href="%20nastarkov.github.io/category/meaning-of-life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Meaning of life</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>%20nastarkov.github.io/%20nastarkov.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Meaning of life</title>
      <link>%20nastarkov.github.io/category/meaning-of-life/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>The meaning of being</title>
      <link>%20nastarkov.github.io/post/%D1%81%D0%BC%D1%8B%D1%81%D0%BB-%D0%B1%D1%8B%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%8F/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>%20nastarkov.github.io/post/%D1%81%D0%BC%D1%8B%D1%81%D0%BB-%D0%B1%D1%8B%D1%82%D0%B8%D1%8F/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The meaning of all human existence lies in being realized through one&amp;rsquo;s own actions. Each of us determines for himself his own values, picture of the world and views. But it often happens that the picture of the world in the mind of a particular person has some mythological overtones. This is due to the fact that the picture of the world is formed under the influence of the past, which was founded by previous generations who lived in this place before us and will live after us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a rule, this picture of the world is represented by various slogans, fanned by all sorts of myths and stereotypes, but not by ancestors, but by contemporaries about ancestors. It is very difficult to talk about the meaning of life and how conscious it is, because each person builds his own system of values ​​based on some specific examples from history. Most often preaches the dominant political ideology or religion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From time immemorial, thinkers from different countries have been thinking about the questions: &amp;ldquo;What is the meaning of being? What does a person live for? What is his goal in this world?&amp;rdquo; Moreover, many philosophers have spent their lives to answer this question, dedicated their writings to this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a simple layman, it all comes down to mundane targets and the list looks something like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding family happiness. Create a family, have children, give them a decent education and live life peacefully and quietly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The acquisition of material wealth and the ability to dispose of them. Many believe that money can buy everything, so they strive to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dedicate your life to science and scientific discoveries. Scientists seek to know the world through science and their research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no point in our existence. All is vanity of vanities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Search for an answer in spiritual manifestations. Some realize themselves in a religious environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Participation in social struggle. Participation in revolutionary movements and opposing organizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suffering. Some people think that suffering is the most human thing about it. They grow, mature, outgrow themselves, and at the moment of their helpless state, when there is no hope for anything, they feel an irresistible desire to change.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
