<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Work with documents | Academic</title>
    <link>nastarkov.github.io/category/work-with-documents/</link>
      <atom:link href="nastarkov.github.io/category/work-with-documents/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Work with documents</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/nastarkov.github.io/media/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Work with documents</title>
      <link>nastarkov.github.io/category/work-with-documents/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Report design</title>
      <link>nastarkov.github.io/post/%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BC%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%B0/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>nastarkov.github.io/post/%D0%BE%D1%84%D0%BE%D1%80%D0%BC%D0%BB%D0%B5%D0%BD%D0%B8%D0%B5-%D0%BE%D1%82%D1%87%D0%B5%D1%82%D0%B0/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;generally-accepted-reporting-standards&#34;&gt;Generally accepted reporting standards&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The R&amp;amp;D report must be made by any printing method on a typewriter or using a computer and a printer on one side of a sheet of A4 white paper at one and a half intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pages of the report should be numbered with Arabic numerals, following continuous numbering throughout the text of the report. The page number is placed in the center of the bottom of the sheet without a dot. The title page is included in the overall page numbering of the report. The page number on the title page is not affixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The font color must be black, the height of letters, numbers and other characters - at least 1.8 mm (point size at least 12). Bold font is not used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text of the report should be printed observing the following margins: right - at least 10 mm, top and bottom - at least 20 mm, left - at least 30 mm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The title page is the first page of the research report and serves as a source of information necessary for processing and searching for the document. The title page must contain the city and year of issue of the work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The approximate volume of the thesis is 50-60 pages of typewritten text, term paper - at least 20 pages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
